# **KHAI EVDAEV**

Brooklyn, NY · +13473071117 · khai.evdaev@gmail.com

#### **EDUCATION**

BOSTON UNIVERSITY Boston, MA

**4 BA Majors**: Maths, CS, Philosophy, Economics Sep 2017 - January 2022

GPA: 3.79 (Magna Cum Laude)

Honors: 1st in class (College Prize 2021) in Computer Science, Philosophy Interdisciplinary

Award, 3 Undergrad Research Awards, Dean's List 2017-2021

Relevant Courses: Real & Complex Analysis, Theory of Algorithms, PDEs and ODEs, Probability,

Mathematical Logic, Data Science, Operating Systems, Distributed Systems.

#### **SUMMARY**

My research interests are broadly in theory of algorithms and complexity, combinatorial optimization and NP hard problems, and mathematical/computational biology. I also have extensive programming experience at the kernel and higher abstraction layers (python, c++).

#### **RESEARCH & WORK EXPERIENCE**

#### **Funded Research on Mathematical Biology**

Sep 2020 - May 2021

- Applied PDEs & ODEs to create a mathematical model for interactions between 2 main signaling proteins (BMP & Nodal) that initiate embryo gastrulation and simulated on Matlab with Finite Difference Approximations
- Programmed and simulated the model on python with finite difference approximation
- Developed a superior model that resembled general behavior of 2 signals by incorporating a bi-stable front equilibrium solution
- Wrote an extensive white-paper describing the model and the simulations

#### **Software Engineer Researcher at Trimble Maps**

Match 2023 - Present

- Solved NP hard combinatorial optimization problems in the routing world: VRP & TSP
- Designed, implemented and tested novel improvement heuristic algorithms for the TSP for over 60k daily clients which secured a \$2mill contract with a customer
- Co-designed a novel algorithm for ranking asymmetricity of a matrix for the TSP and used it for QA testing of a client product
- Collaborated and lead an intern on a research project and lead team discussions on software engineering practices
- Read algorithmic theory and mathematics research papers in order to find innovative and optimal solutions to problems from the routing world

## Software Engineer at SambaNova Systems

#### September 2022 - March 2023

- Designed & implemented a Network Fabric Management daemon for next generation Al Accelerator
- Implemented the end-to-end Fabric Manager encompassing both User and Kernel space in over 2k lines of C
- Presented design document and implementation choice along with git code review sessions with the entire team
- Successfully verified Fabric Manager functionality in an emulation environment and integrated with software stack
- Delivered the design, implementation and verification of the Fabric Manager in 3 months

## Funded Research on Mathematical Philosophy of Plato

Jan 2019 - May 2019

- Investigated the epistemological questions raised in Plato's *Republic* concerning the nature of mathematics
- Wrote a series of mini essays that describe the *Divided Line* and *Cave* allegories in relation to theory of knowledge
- Critiqued modern viewpoints on the nature of mathematics in empirical science

#### **Funded Research on Aristotelian Ethics**

Jul 2018 - September 2018

- Spend a summer in St. Petersburg Russia to conduct a social experiment on Aristotle's *Nicomachean Ethics* regarding the nature of the ultimate good (*eudamonia*)
- Wrote a journal about the conversations with the people about the nature of happiness

# **Internship and Projects**

## A Distributed Cloud Computing Project with Red Hat

Sep 2021 - Dec 2021

- Began porting into Ceph 25% of a superior caching architecture i/o operation to write a faster Amazon S3 get function via remote read caches and a key-value global/centralized directory
- Handled a complex C++ codebase comprised of thousands of lines and minimal commenting by developers
- Collaborated and lead a team of 4 members in an Agile environment with responsible communication

#### Implementation of a Distributed Consensus Algorithm Raft

Jan 2021 - May 2021

- Implemented Raft in Go lang in over 1.5k lines and passed over 30 critical tests
- Studied leader election, synchronization, snapshots, availability and consistency to achieve a near 100% score

# **TEACHING EXPERIENCE**

# TA for CS330 Algorithms Class at BU

Jan 2019 - Jan 2021

- Taught classes of 30 students on algorithm fundamentals: BFS/DFS, Dijkstra's, Divide-and-Conquer, DynamicProgramming, NP & NP-C; explained how to prove correctness & execution time of algorithms via 3 methods
- Managed 8 graders to accomplish the fastest turnover rate in the course history at BU
- Developed 9 detailed and technical tutorial videos for each algorithm and topic

# **SKILLS**

Computer Languages: C, C++, Linux & Bash, Python, GO, MatLab.